I'm not ashamed. I've known love. I've known rejection. I'm not afraid to declare my feelings.
我不感到羞愧，我懂得爱 我懂得拒绝 我也不怕坦白我的感受
Take trust, for instance, or friendship. These are the important things in life.
举例来说，信任，或者友谊 这些都是生命中最重要的
These are the things that matter, that help you on your way.
它们对你有很大的帮助
If you can't trust your friends, well what then? What then?
如果你无法相信你的朋友们 那怎么办？怎么办？
This could have been any city.
这个故事可能发生在任何城市
They're all the same.
都一样
Hello. I've come about the room.
你好！我是来看房子的
- So what's his name? - I don't know. Campbell or something.
- 他叫什么名字？ - 我不知道。好象叫“坎贝尔"还是什么的
- Cameron. - Cameron? Really?
- 卡梅伦 - 卡梅伦？真的？
That's right.
是的
What?
什么？
- Are you comfortable? - Yes, thanks.
- 你还好吗？ - 我很好，谢谢
- Have you seen the flat? - Yes.
- 你已经看过那个公寓了？ - 是的
- And you like it? - Yes, it's great.
- 你喜欢吗？ - 是的，很棒
We all like it. The room's nice, too, don't you think?
我们都喜欢，那个房间很好，你不觉得吗？
Spacious, bright, all that sort of stuff, all that sort of crap.
宽敞，明亮，诸如此类，真他妈的好
Well, yes.
是啊
So tell me, cos I'd like to know, what on earth could make you think...
那我想知道一件事，到底为什么使你认为...
..we'd want to share this flat with someone like you?
我们想和你分享如此好的公寓呢？
My first impression is that you have none of the qualities we seek from a flatmate.
我对你的第一印象很糟，在你身上找不到 一个好室友的优良品质
I'm talking about things like presence, charisma, style and charm.
比如说举止，魅力，品味，吸引力等等
I don't think we're asking too much, or being unreasonable.
我并不认为我们的要求很过份或者苟刻
Take David here. An accountant he may be, but at least he tries hard.
大卫住进这里，因为他很卖力， 虽然他也许只是个会计
Trouble is, I just don't think you're trying.
问题是，我看不出来，你有多么努力
Hey, Cameron, I mean this. Good luck.
嘿，卡梅伦，说真的，祝你好运
- Just a few questions. - What about your hobbies?
- 问几个问题 - 你的兴趣是什么？
- Why do you want a room here? - Do you smoke?
- 你为什么希望住这里？ - 你抽烟吗？
When you sacrifice a goat and rip its heart out, do you summon hellfire?
当你供奉一只羊，并把它的心取出来时 你会召唤地狱之火吗？
It's a straightforward question. Either you're divorced or you're not.
这是个很直接的问题，你离婚了没有？
- Or do you just send out for a pizza? - Do a little freebase, maybe?
- 或者，你刚刚叫了比萨？ - 你偶尔吸一点点可卡因吗？
How do you decide which shade of black to wear?
你选的黑衣服一般黑到什么程度？
OK, I'm going to play you just a few seconds of this tape.
我会播放几秒钟这盘磁带上的音乐
Name the song, the lead singer,...
说出歌名，和主唱...
..and three hit singles subsequently recorded by him with another band.
以及后来他和他的乐队推出的三首单曲
Let me get this straight. This affair that you're "not" having,...
直截了当的说吧，你所谓“没有”的这段情...
..is it not with a man or not with a woman?
是和一个男人还是一个女人？
Turning very briefly to corporate financing...
回到共同资金的问题上...
No, this is important. Leveraged buyouts: a good or a bad thing?
不，这点很重要，杠杆收购是好事还是坏事？
When did anyone last say to you these exact words:
最后一个和你说这些话的人是谁：
"You are the sunshine of my life"?
“你是我生命中的阳光”？
And how would you react, then, if I told you I was the Antichrist?
如果我告诉你我是个反基督者，你有何反应？
Do you like my picture?
你喜欢我的照片吗？
Defeat. Defeat. Defeat.
打败他，打败他，打败他
Sporting, personal, financial, professional, sexual and everything.
体育爱好，私人状况，经济情况， 职业，性别，所有的一切
Next.
下一个
- Did you know that...? - Alex. Just serve.
- 你知道...？ - 亚历克斯，发球
Anyway, I wasn't tryin' to win. I don't want to devalue your victory, Juliet.
我并不是想获胜， 我只是不想贬低你的胜利，朱丽叶
- I wasn't tryin' to win. - Victory's the same as defeat.
- 我没有想胜过你 - 胜利和失败是一样的
It's giving in to destructive urges.
它是对破坏本能的屈服
Did you learn that in your psychotherapy group?
你是不是从心理治疗小组那里学到的？
- Discussion group. - I thought you'd stopped going.
- 讨论小组 - 我还以为你早就不去了
He had too many of those urges. You of all people should know about that.
他有太多的欲望了， 你们这些人都应该知道这一点
God, you two are sensitive.
天啊，你们两个很敏感呢
All I'm doing is implying some kind of ugly, sordid, sexual liaison.
我现在只不过是在暗示 某种丑陋，肮脏，性的交易
- I'd be proud of that. - Maybe you should go.
- 我应该为此而骄傲 - 你也许也应该参加
- You'll meet someone wonderful. - For my life?
- 说不定你会遇见一个不错的 - 找个一生相伴的人？
- A discussion group? I think not. - For the flat.
- 就在这么一个讨论小组是？我看不可能 - 找个人住这个公寓
No, it'd be someone like him, and one's enough, thank you very much.
不，恐怕会找个和他一样的人 他那样的，一个就够了，拜托你了
What about that girl? That friend of yours, the one that came round. I liked her.
那个女孩呢？你的那个朋友， 来过的那个，我喜欢她
We had something. She could have moved in. We had chemistry.
我们似乎有点感觉，她本可以搬进来住啊， 我们很投缘
- She hated you... - She had problems.
- 她恨你... - 那她有问题
..more than anyone she had ever met in her entire life.
你比她所遇见过的任何人都更恨
Like they say, you know, she's got to want to change, hasn't she?
就象他们说的那样，她曾经希望改变， 可是有吗？
- You must be Hugo. - And you must be Juliet.
- 你一定就是雨果 - 你一定就是朱丽叶
- Would you like to come in? - I'd be delighted.
- 请进 - 多谢
- What do you do? - I've been away for a while.
- 你做什么工作？ - 我离开过一段时间
Travelling. And now I'm writing a novel.
去旅行。现在我在写一本小说
Oh.
哦
- What's it about? - It's actually about a priest who dies.
- 关于什么？ - 关于一个牧师之死的故事
I see.
了解
Maybe you're right. Maybe I ought to change it. You're right.
也许你是对的， 也许我是应该改变一下，你是对的
I mean, who wants to read another story about a dead priest?
我是指，有谁愿意 读一本关于死牧师的故事呢？
In fact, it's about another guy, he's not a priest, and he lives.
实际上，那是关于另一个男人 他不是牧师，而且活着
He doesn't die. See? It's better already.
他没有死，看到了没？这样好多了
- Writing seems easy. - It's a breeze. No problem.
- 写作好象很容易啊 - 易如反掌，没问题
Do you think you could answer that?
你可以接一下吗？
- What, the telephone? - But... if it's for me, I'm not here.
- 什么，电话？ - 但是...如果是我的，就说我不在
Right. You're not here.
好的，你不在
OK.
好
Hello?
你好？
Yes, it is, yes. Who's calling, please?
是，对，是，请问你是哪位？
Well, I'm sorry, but she's not... she's not in right now.
对不起，但她不... 她现在不在这里
No, I've got absolutely no idea.
不，我一点也不知道
Would you like to leave a message?
你愿意留个口信吗？
OK. Goodbye.
好的，再见
That was, um... a guy called Brian.
这是个，嗯...，叫布赖恩的男的
- Did he sound upset? - A little bit, yeah.
- 他是不是听起来很紧张 - 有一点，对
- Is that good or bad? - It's an improvement.
- 是好还是不好？ - 有进步
- Shall I get the phone?
我是不是该接电话？
Just leave it. He knows I'm probably at home. I'm working nights this week.
随它去，他知道我可能在家 我这周上夜班
- You're working nights? - I'm a doctor.
- 你上夜班？ - 我是个医生
Ah.
是
- And he's a patient? - No, but he needs treatment.
- 他是个病人？ - 不是，但他需要治疗
- For what? - A certain weakness.
- 治疗什么？ - 某种衰弱症
- The human condition. - Oh. You know about it.
- 人类生存条件 - 哦，你对那个很了解
- Well, I write about it. - And that's not the same thing?
- 我写过关于它的东西 - 不是一样吗？
No. I'm like all novelists - on a search of the self.
不一样，我喜欢小说家， 因为他们总是探索自我
Has he tried down the back of the fridge?
他是不是累的倒在冰箱后面了？
He seemed like a nice guy, Alex.
他好象不错，亚历克斯
I'm not saying he didn't seem like a nice guy.
我又没说他不是
I just said it's a bit strange, this search of the self or whatever.
我只是觉得有点怪异，所谓探索自我什么的
He didn't seem strange, Alex.
他并不怪啊，亚历克斯
He seemed... you know,...
他好象...就是...
- ..interesting. - Interesting?
- ...有意思 - 有意思？
- Interesting.
有意思
Hello? No, she's not in.
你好？不，她不在
I don't know. I've no idea.
我不知道，不清楚
- Who was it? - I don't know. He sounded Swedish.
- 是谁？ - 不知道，听上去象是瑞典口音
- Do you know any Swedish men? - No.
- 你认识什么瑞典人吗？ - 不认识
Maybe it was just the emotion.
也许只是感觉吧
- What do you think? - About what?
- 你觉得呢？ - 觉得什么？
- About this Hugo person. - I don't have the time.
- 关于那个雨果的人 - 我没时间
- I'm just asking what you think. - I don't care, so long as he's not a freak.
- 我只是问，你感觉如何 - 我不在乎，到目前为止，他还不象是个怪人
David. It's your mother's handwriting. I didn't open it.
大卫，这是你妈妈的笔迹 我没有打开过
I don't like reading about your father's constipation.
我可不想听到你爸爸便秘的事
- So we'll meet him, then? - What?
- 我们会和他会面，然后呢？ - 什么？
Yeah, yeah, whatever. I tell you, every letter this guy writes you is the same.
好吧，随便，我跟你说， 这个家伙写的每一封信都是一样的
They all begin like true love and descend into open pornography.
开始写的都很纯情，接着就变成色情文学了
"I dream of your thighs, the touch of your white skin leading me in desire,...
“我梦见你的大腿， 触摸你白皙的肌肤令我浮想连篇...”
..while I, aroused and inflamed..." Aroused and inflamed?
- ...当我，勃起的，红肿的...” - 勃起的，红肿的？
He even signs them in his own name.
他甚至用自己的真名署名
I'd sign someone else's. I'd sign his name. If I wrote them, that is, which I don't.
我宁可用其它人的名字，比如用他的名字 要是我写的话，不过我可不会写
Interesting. That's what she said.
有意思，她是这么描述你的
Interesting. You see, that's why you're here.
有意思，你看，这就是为什么你会在这儿
I don't usually meet people, unless I already know them.
通常我不会和一般人会面，除非和我认识的人
- I see. - People can be so cruel.
- 知道了 - 有时，人类很残酷
So, um...
那，嗯...
..well, we think it's fine.
...我们认为很好
Ah. So, I can have the room?
啊，那么我可以住进这个房间了？
- Yes, you can have the room. - I'm not usually drunk.
- 是的，你可以住进来 - 我并不经常喝醉酒的
- Not usually this drunk. - Only on expenses.
- 没有这么醉 - 谈谈费用
He's going to tell you he could have been someone.
他要告诉你，他本来可以出名的
Instead of what he is, which is the man we know and love.
而不象现在这样，但我们喜欢现在的他
..tired out, empty shell of a... Know and love?
- ...疲倦，空虚... - 理解与爱?
- I think you're lying. - You're right.
- 我觉得你在说谎 - 你说的对
- You see? They don't really know me. - No, Alex. We don't really love you.
- 你看见了？他们并不真正了解我 - 不，亚历克斯，我们并不真正爱你
Can you afford this place?
你可以付的起这个房间的价格吗？
Oh, yeah.
哦，当然可以
- Can I ask you a question? - Certainly.
- 我可以问你一个问题吗？ - 当然可以
Have you ever killed a man?
你曾杀过人吗？
No.
没有
That's fair enough, then.
那就好
Well, it certainly smells like the real thing.
它闻起来象真的
Rangers have made a few dramatic comebacks this season.
罗杰斯队在这个赛季有了一些起色
But they'll really have to draw on all of their resources.
但他们不得不全力以赴
- Have you seen Hugo? - No.
- 你有没有见到雨果？ - 没有
Any idea which channel he's on?
你知道他在哪个频道里吗？
..the High Court in Edinburgh.
...爱丁堡的最高法院
Oh, for fuck's sake.
去你妈的
No, she's not in.
不，她不在
- Have you seen him? - I don't have the time.
- 你有没有见过他？ - 我没有时间了
- Yes or no? David, yes or...? - No!
- 是或否？大卫，是或...? - 否！
- David hasn't seen him either. - So I gathered.
- 大卫也没有见过他 - 我也是这么想的
- Maybe he didn't like us. - David?
- 也许他不喜欢我们 - 大卫？
- No, Hugo. - His car's still there.
- 不，雨果 - 他的车还在那儿
- He's got a car? - Yeah. What's wrong with that?
- 他有车？ - 是的，有什么问题？
- What sort of car? - I don't know, Alex. I'm just a girl.
- 什么样的车？ - 我不知道，亚历克斯，我是个女孩啊
I'll ask you once more. What sort of car?
我再问你一次，什么样的车？
A blue one, OK? And it's still there.
蓝色的，好了吧？它还在那儿呢
Hugo, I'm sorry about this, but can you open your door?
雨果，很抱歉，你可以开开门吗？
It's us, your flatmates and companions, your new-found friends.
是我们，你的室友，你的新朋友们
- He's not there. I can't see him at all. - Maybe he's in the wardrobe.
- 他不在，我一点也看不见他 - 也许他躲在衣柜里
Of course he's not in the bloody wardrobe.
他当然不会在该死的衣柜里
- It's a joke, Alex. - I think he probably left.
- 不过是个笑话，亚历克斯 - 我想他大概离开了
- We'll probably never see him again. - Alex, the key is on the other side.
- 我们大概再也见不到他了 - 亚历克斯，钥匙在另一头
- So? - Open it.
- 如何？ - 打开它
You want me to kick this in? Now?
你要我踢开它？现在？
- Yeah. - OK, no problem.
- 是的 - 好，没问题
Do you want a go?
你想来一下吗？
OK, you size that up.
好，你估计一下
- Is this what they always look like? - Yes.
- 人死了是不是都这个样子？ - 是
- Wonder how he did it. - Did what?
- 我在想他是怎么做的 - 做什么？
Killed himself. I presume that's what's happened.
自杀，我想是这样的
What do you think?
你认为呢？
- Alex! - What? What's wrong?
- 亚历克斯！ - 什么？有什么问题？
- What are you doing? - Looking.
- 你在干什么？ - 看
- Don't. - Don't look?
- 不要 - 不要看？
- No. - Why not?
- 不 - 为什么不？
What's wrong? Don't you wonder what he died from?
有什么问题？你就不怀疑他是怎么死的？
No. The guy's dead. What more do you need?
不，那家伙已经死了 你还想要什么？
It's not every day I find a story in my own flat.
这可不是每天发生在我公寓的故事
It's not a story, Alex, it's a corpse.
这不是个故事，亚历克斯，这是个死尸
I've never seen a dead body before.
我从来没见过死人
I saw my grandmother, of course, but I don't suppose that counts.
当然我见过我的祖母，不过我想那不算数
She was alive at the time.
她那时还活着
Can I show you something?
你能过来看一样东西吗？
Emergency. Which service?
紧急呼叫中心，需要什么服务？
Emergency. Which... ?
紧急呼叫中心，需要什么...?
- No. - Just think about it.
- 不 - 想想而已
- Come on, David.
- 拜托，大卫
- No. - Juliet?
- 不 - 朱丽叶？
- No, Alex. It's... - It's what?
- 不，亚历克斯，它... - 它什么？
- Unfeasible. - Is that all?
- 不可能的 - 就这些？
- You mean immoral. - I know what I mean.
- 你的意思是“不道德”？ - 我知道我在说什么
- I'm only asking you to think about it. - It's a sick idea, Alex. It's sick.
- 我只是请你想象一下 - 这是邪恶的想法，亚历克斯，这不好
But don't tell me you're not tempted. Don't tell me you're not interested.
别告诉我，你一点都不动心 别告诉我，你一点都不感兴趣
- I know you well enough. - You think so?
- 我太了解你了 - 你这么认为？
Go ahead, then. Telephone.
去吧，那你去打电话吧
Telephone the police.
打给警察
Go ahead. No one's gonna stand in your way.
去吧，没人会阻止你
Telephone them. Tell them.
打电话给他们，告诉他们
Tell them there's a suitcase full of money, and you don't want it.
告诉他们有一个手提箱里装满了钱 而且你不想要
Was there a pet in the house? Yeah, a pet.
房间里是不是有宠物？是的，有一个
You know, like a dog or a budgie or a gerbil or something?
比如狗，鹦鹉，沙鼠，或什么？
What I need here is "PC Plod saves Harry the Hamster from house of horror".
我需要的是“电脑把小老鼠从恐怖屋拯救出来”
All right. Well, that's a pity. You see, no pets - no human angle.
好的，可惜 你看，没有宠物 - 没有人间角落
- Hi, there. What happened to that guy? - What guy?
- 喂，你，那个家伙怎么了？ - 那个家伙？
That guy. The one that died.
那个死掉的家伙
- Died? - That one last week.
- 死掉的？ - 上个礼拜死掉的那个
- Here? - Yes, here. Where else?
- 这里？ - 是，这里，还有哪里？
Oh, him. Well, he died.
哦，他啊，他死了
That's what I thought.
我也是这么想的
Hello? Have you got room for an overnighter?
你好？你有没有放小行李的房间
- He's still here? - Yeah, he couldn't get his car started.
- 他还在这儿？ - 是的，因为他没办法发动他的车
When are you gonna let the police know?
你什么时候告诉警察？
You phone them if you want, David.
随时都可以啊，只要你愿意，大卫
- What about you? - I'm getting used to having him around.
- 那你呢？ - 我已经习惯他在周围了
What is it we do here, David?
我们在这儿做什么，大卫？
- Sorry? - Here.
- 什么？ - 这儿
- Right here? - In this firm.
- 这儿？ - 这个公司
- Well, it's a wide range of... - Accounting, David.
- 这个问题范围很广... - 会计学，大卫
Chartered accounting is of ten sneered at. Were you aware of that?
特许会计是受人嘲笑的，你意识到了吗？
- Not any real sneering as such, no. - There's a whole wide world out there,...
- 并不是所有的都象它一样受人嘲笑 - 外面的世界很大...
..and it all needs to be accounted for, does it not?
所有的都需要会计去计算，不是吗？
- Well, I... - They sneer, do they not?
- 我... - 他们爱嘲笑，不是吗？
- I'm not sure. - It's unfashionable.
- 我不敢肯定 - 它不流行
But yes, we're methodical, yes, we're diligent, yes, we're serious.
不过是的，我们有条不紊，我们努力，认真
And where's the crime in that? Why not shout it from the rooftops?
那里面发生了什么问题呢？ 为什么不在屋顶喊叫呢？
Maybe sometimes we're a wee bit boring, but, by God, we get the job done.
也许我们有点令人讨厌， 但是，我们把工作完成了
- Yes, sir. - That's why I think you fit in here.
- 是的，先生 - 那就是我认为你合适留在这里的原因
- I'm boring? - You get the job done.
- 我很无趣？ - 但你可以把工作完成的很好
- I see. I thought you meant... - Which is why I trust you with this client.
- 我知道了，我以为你是指... - 这就是为什么我放心的让你去接这个客户
Good morning. Can I help you?
早上好，有什么可以帮忙的吗？
Yeah, I'll just check that for you.
是的，我帮你看一下
Let's do it.
干吧
Let's talk about disposal. We have to make that body unidentifiable.
我们先谈谈怎么处理 我们必须令尸体无法分辨
Burning, dumping at sea and burial are all flawed,...
火烧、扔进海里、掩埋都有问题...
..either by fingerprints or more commonly by dental records, I have learnt.
据我所知，都可以查到指纹或牙齿档案
What I suggest is that we bury him out in the forest.
我建议，把他埋到树林里
First we remove his hands and his feet, which we incinerate.
首先，我们把他的手和脚卸下来，烧掉
And his teeth, which we just remove. It's as simple as that.
还有他的牙齿，只要除掉就行 和那些活一样简单
David.
大卫
I've always wondered what these were for. Now...
我一直在想这些都是派什么用的，现在...
Oh.
哦
This is what we need.
这是我们要的
And, um...
而且，嗯...
..this.
...这个
- What else? - I don't know.
- 还要什么？ - 我不知道
A spade. We need a spade.
一个铁锹，我们需要一个铁锹
I wish you'd concentrate. We need a spade to dig a pit.
我希望你精神集中一点 我们需要一个铁锹挖一个坑
- Who's gonna do it? - Dig the pit?
- 谁会去做？ - 挖坑？
- Not that. - Who's gonna do what?
- 不是那个 - 谁做什么？
- You know what I'm talking about. - Do I? What are you talking about?
- 你知道我在说什么 - 是吗？你在说什么？
- You know what. Who's gonna do it? - We all are, David.
- 你知道的，谁会去做？ - 我们一起，大卫
We're all gonna do it. You, me and Juliet will do his or her bit. Fair enough?
我们一起做，你，我，还有朱丽叶 每个人都有份，公平吗？
- I can't do it. - I don't hear this.
- 我做不了 - 我听不见
- I won't be able to do it. - You want out already?
- 我没办法做 - 你已经打算退出了？
You don't want the money? Hugo is going off! He smells!
你不想得到那些钱？ 雨果已经开始腐烂了，他已经发臭了！
- The flat smells! We can't wait! - I won't be able to cut him up.
- 公寓也臭了！我们不能再等了！ - 我没办法把他分尸
- Who's going to do it? - I thought we all were.
- 谁会去做？ - 我认为我们应该一起做
- I don't think I can. - But, Juliet, you're a doctor.
- 我觉得我做不到 - 但是，朱丽叶，你是个医生
- You kill people every day. - That's different. I still don't want to.
- 你每天都在杀人 - 不一样的，我还是不想做
Now you tell me.
你现在才告诉我这个！
There's something I want to ask.
有件事我想问
I don't know! I swear to God, I don't know!
我不知道！我向上帝发誓，我不知道！
Family? Friends?
家人？朋友？
Drugged-up, wandering, suicidal fuck-ups don't have families.
抓起来，想想看，自杀的那些杂种没有家人
- I just thought we should discuss it. - Take his legs.
- 我本以为我们可以讨论一下 - 拿起他的腿
Where's Hugo?
雨果在哪里？
- Pick him up. - Shh.
- 把他提起来 - 嘘
I swear to God, I don't know! I don't know!
我向上帝发誓，我不知道，我不知道！
Stupid fuckin' bastard.
愚蠢的狗杂种
Why don't we draw lots for it?
要不然我们抽签决定？
Whoever draws the short straw does it all. That way you either do it or you don't.
谁抽到短的，就让他一个人干 这样，你要么别干，要么就干完！
- OK. I can go with that. - David?
- 好，我可以 - 大卫?
- I don't know. - If I draw the short straw, I'll do it.
- 我不知道 - 如果我抽到短的，我来做
But I'm not gonna do it just because you won't.
但如果你不肯干，我是绝对不会干的
All right, then. Here we are and this is it.
好吧，就这么说定了
Do you wanna play or not?
你到底参加不参加？
I can't do it.
我做不了
- Finished. - All right, but not quite.
- 完成了 - 好，但还没完全结束
- Is that going to be deep enough? - Don't worry.
- 深度够吗？ - 别担心
- Is this necessary? - Yes. Now come on. All or nothin'.
- 有必要吗？ - 是的，别废话了，要么别做，要么做完
- Are you all right? - Oh, yes. I'm fine, thanks. Just fine.
- 你还好吧？ - 哦，是的，我很好，谢谢，很好
- Would you like to talk about it? - No.
- 你想说出来吗？ - 不
These three people get their chance to...
这三个人都有机会...
..lose a million.
失去一百万
Yes, all right. Hello there and welcome aboard our millionaire's yacht.
是的。大家好， 欢迎来到我们的百万游艇节目
It's just like the "Marie Celeste" but without the party atmosphere.
就好象是“玛丽・斯莱斯特”， 只不过缺少了派对气氛
As you know, the object is not to win the game, but to...
正如你们所知， 我们节目的目标不是赢，而是...
Lose.
输
Not to give right answers, but...
不是给出正确的答案，而是...
- Wrong ones. - Not to do well, but to do really...
- 错误的答案 - 不是要做的好，而是要做的...
Badly.
糟糕
And above all to try and make a total... hotchpotch.
最重要的是努力做成一个...大杂烩
Be careful.
小心了
Alex!
亚历克斯!
I don't know why we couldn't stuff it under the floorboards.
我不明白为什么不能藏在下面
- Stop nagging, Alex. - We could have hid it in the fridge.
- 不要罗嗦，亚历克斯 - 我们原本可以把它藏在冰箱里
Ladies and gentlemen, could I have your attention, please?
先生们，女士们，请注意了
I'd like to thank you all for coming tonight,...
感谢大家今天来到这里...
..to help us raise funds for the sick children's unit.
帮助我们为疾病儿童基金会筹集基金
You never told me this was for children. I hate children.
你从来没跟我说过这是为了儿童，我讨厌儿童
I'd raise money to have the little fuckers put down. I want my money back!
我宁可捐钱杀了那帮小王八蛋 把钱还给我！
But before the dancing starts...
在跳舞开始之前...
- Excuse me! - ..I would like to give a vote of thanks...
- 对不起 - ...我希望投票以感谢...
..to the few people who have worked so hard to make this occasion happen.
那些为了这一切辛勤工作的人们
- Do you know these people? - They're my friends.
- 你认识这些人吗？ - 他们是我的朋友
Oh, so if they want to speak to you, we tell them that you're not here?
哦，那如果他们想和你说话， 我们就告诉他们你不在？
But ladies and gentlemen and those of you who are neither or both...
但是先生们和女士们以及其它的...
- Where did they dig him up? - Form sets for "Strip the Willow".
- 他们在哪里发现他的？ - 奏一曲“剥柳树叶舞曲”
- Are we going to dance? - Well, it's physical contact, isn't it?
- 我们跳舞去吗？ - 那可是肉体接触啊，不是吗？
OK.
好
Talk to me.
告诉我
- OK. - No! Don't! Please don't!
- 好 - 不！不要！请不要！
No! No!
不！不！
Please!
求你了！
- Can we talk about something? - Not now. I have an idea.
- 我们可以谈谈吗？ - 现在不行，我不知道
- It's important. We need to decide... - Will you just stop worrying?
- 这很重要，我们需要决定... - 你能不能不要再担心了？
To love and to happiness for ever.
为了爱和永远的快乐
For ever and ever.
永远永远
- What's wrong? - I want to talk now.
- 怎么了？ - 我有话要说
When you've drunk to love and happiness.
除非你为了爱和永远的快乐而醉倒以后
- Now. - After.
- 现在 - 以后
David, I promise we will. Just keep him happy.
大卫，我保证我们会让他一直快乐
It's not for me. It's for love and happiness for ever.
不是为了我，是为了爱和永远的快乐
Look over there. It's Cameron.
看那边，是卡梅伦
- Who? - You remember Cameron.
- 谁？ - 你记得卡梅伦吗
- No. - What's he doing here?
- 不 - 他在这儿干什么？
- That's not him. - It is. Cameron!
- 不是他 - 就是他。卡梅伦！
Cameron, come on over here. Come on.
卡梅伦，过来，过来
What?
什么？
Nothing. We thought you were someone else.
没什么，我们以为你是另一个人
Good luck!
祝你好运！
- Why does he have to follow us around? - What I was wanting to say was this.
- 他为什么老跟着我们？ - 我想说的是这个
Aha!
啊哈！
- The divine Juliet. Long time no see. - Brian.
- 可爱的朱丽叶，好久不见了 - 布赖恩
- Would you care to dance? - Hold on. Who do you think you are?
- 你可以和我跳一支舞吗？ - 等一下，你以为你是什么人？
- What? - Who do you think you are?
- 什么？ - 你以为你是什么人？
- You interrupted us. - I'm Brian McKinley. And who are you?
- 你打断我们的对话 - 我是布赖恩・麦金利，你是谁？
Well, Brian McKinley, if you wanna talk to my girlfriend, you talk to me first.
好，布赖恩・麦金利，你要是想 和我的女朋友跳舞，先要过我这一关
If you wanna dance, you apply three weeks in advance,...
你要是想跳舞，先提前三周申请...
..or you're gonna end up inside a fucking bin bag!
...要不然，你会死在他妈的垃圾袋里
You didn't apply, so you don't dance.
你没有申请，所以别想跳舞
Do you think you could be a little more forceful next time?
你觉得下次你会更暴力吗？
- I'm sorry. - No, no. I think he got the message.
- 对不起 - 不，不，我想他已经领会了
That was quite stressful.
刚才真是紧张
Yeah, but you were good. He was really good. Fuckin' bin bag, I like that.
是，但你刚才真棒。他真棒 他妈的垃圾袋，我爱这个词
You really explored your maleness to the full there.
你真是体现了你的阳刚之气
- You think so? - You certainly had a good look around.
- 真的？ - 你刚才做的漂亮极了
You were magnificent.
你太棒了
Yeah.
是
Fuckin' bin bag.
他妈的垃圾袋
Cameron! What a surprise!
卡梅伦！吓我一跳！
Hello?
你好？
- Who was it? - I don't know.
- 是谁？ - 我不知道
- No one said anything. - Or rendered speechless with desire.
- 没人说过 - 或者是他自己想一言不发
I recall that feeling from the days when I had such a thing.
我又回想起了那些日子的感觉
- Are you all right? - No.
- 你还好吗？ - 不好
Then let's spend some money.
那我们花点钱吧
Hello. It's been a struggle, but now our days of worry are over.
你好，这段日子的确是很艰难， 但担惊受怕的日子已经结束了
The light at the end of the tunnel has expanded into a golden sunrise.
通道尽头的光线已经变成了金色的阳光
And now at last, at long last, nothing will ever be the same again.
在最后，漫长的最后， 任何事情都不会再相同
This is Alex Law reporting on the video diary of his own life.
这是来自亚历克斯・劳私人视频日记的报道
Let me tell you, I'm so happy I could die.
我告诉你，我开心死了
I think we ought to stop this, don't you?
我觉得我们应该停止了，好吗？
- Oh, will you relax? - You're making us all nervous.
- 哦，你放松一下好吗？ - 你让我们都很紧张
- How much did you pay for this? - I don't know.
- 你为这个花了多少钱？ - 我不知道
- I can't remember. - Tell me how much you paid.
- 我不记得了 - 告诉我你花了多少钱
- How much did you pay for this?
- 你到底花了多少钱？
- No idea. I don't know. - How much did you pay for this?!
- 不知道，不知道 - 到底花了多少钱？！
- 500. - 500?
- 500块 - 500块？
You paid 500 for this?
你为了这个花了500块？
- That's what it cost. - No. That's what you paid for it.
- 它就是这个价格 - 不，是你花了这么多在这上面！
500 is what you paid for it. We don't know how much it cost us yet.
你花了500块在这上面 我们目前还不知道这东西的代价是什么
For you two to have a good time. We don't know the cost of that yet.
你们两个倒是逍遥 但代价是什么，我们并不知道
Excuse me. Did they take anything?
对不起，他们拿了什么吗？
Is that enough for you?
这些够了吗？
Oi.
吃的
- What? - Is that enough for you?
- 什么？ - 这些够了没有？
- Yes, that's fine. - There's plenty more.
- 是，够了 - 还有很多
That's fine.
够了
- What's wrong? - Nothing.
- 怎么了？ - 没什么
- You're not eating. - Eating what?
- 你不吃饭 - 吃什么？
- You're not eating like you used to. - If you give me the plate, I'll eat.
- 你不象以前那吃东西了 - 你把碟子给我，我会吃的
Now swallow.
现在，给我狼吞虎咽
You should spend some money instead of worrying about it.
你应该花点钱， 而不应该老是担心，这是我给你的建议
- You'd feel much better. - Once it's spent, you don't have to worry.
- 你会感觉好很多 - 一旦花掉它，你就不担心了
- It'll be a weight off your shoulders. - You know we're right.
- 它象是担子从身上卸掉了 - 你明白这个道理
- I wanna secure it. - Secure it? You wanna put it in a bank?
- 我要把保证它的安全 - 保证它的安全？你打算把它存到银行里吗？
You don't wanna put it in a bank, do you? Do you want to bury it?
你不会是想存到银行里吧？ 你想把它埋起来？
- I don't see the point. It's stupid. - Course it's stupid. We took the money.
- 我不明白，这是很蠢的 - 这本来就很蠢，我们拿了这笔钱
It was a material calculation.
这是很实际的想法
What's the point if it's underground in some funny bank in some funny place?
如果这钱是在某个秘密的银行里 或其它什么地方，有什么意义呢？
If you can't have it - spend it - then what use is it? None.
如果你不能拥有它，挥霍它， 那它还有什么用呢？什么用也没有！
It's all for nothing. I didn't get into this for nothing, so that I could have nothing.
所有的都白费了，我不想白费心血 那样我就什么都没有了
Yeah, and you didn't saw his feet off.
是，你又没有看到他腿被锯断的样子
Tastes different.
不一样的感觉
David, what are you doin' up there?
大卫，你在上面干什么？
Will you come down now? It's not safe up there.
你现在可以下来吗？上面不安全
Are you listening to me?
你听到我说的吗？
Security and insanity are not the same thing.
安全和疯狂不是一回事
Shit.
妈的
I don't care. A grown man shouldn't be living in a loft. He isn't safe up there.
我不管，一个成人不应该住在阁楼上 他在上面不安全
If you cared about him at all, you'd use your influence to get him down.
如果你在乎他，你应该说服他下来
- And the money? - We could put it somewhere.
- 那钱呢？ - 我们可以放到其它地方
Where he can't get it?
放到他找不到的地方？
Well, you thought of that, not me.
这是你的主意，不是我的
Forget it. He'll come down.
算了，他会下来的
Oh, Juliet, look.
哦，朱丽叶，听我说
Hello, Mr Lumsden. It's David Stevens here.
你好，朗姆斯顿先生，这里是大卫・史蒂文斯
I'm sorry, sir. I won't be able to make it to the office today.
对不起，先生，我今天去不了公司了
It's my mother, sir. She's very ill and I think I need to be with her just now.
是我妈妈，先生，她病的很重 我想，现在我应该陪在她身边
I don't know. The doctors aren't sure. It could go either way.
我不知道，医生也不能肯定，都有可能
Yes, sir. I'll certainly stay in touch.
是的，先生，我会保持联系的
- Good day? - What?
- 好天？ - 什么？
- What are you talking about?
- 你在说什么？
- I'm just asking if you had a good day. - Why?
- 我只想问你今天过的好不好 - 为什么？
Well, I thought I'd make conversation.
我想我们可以谈谈
- Please, I'd rather you didn't.
请你不要这样
- Are you expecting anyone? - No.
- 你在等什么人吗？ - 没有
- Aren't you going to answer it? - Well, I'm not expecting anyone either.
- 你不打算去开门？ - 我也没有在等什么人
It's in the loft! In the loft!
在阁楼，在阁楼！
September 19, London Heathrow to Rio de Janeiro.
9月19日，伦敦希思罗机场到里约热内卢
It's British Airways. You're looking at 765. That's 7-6-5.
是英国航空公司，你选的是765，是7- 6- 5
- That sounds fine. - Air Portugal, on the other hand,...
- 听起来不错 - 葡萄牙航空公司，在另一方面...
..it's via Lisbon, the same day. It's 565. 5-6-5. Is catering important?
途经里斯本，同一天，是565 5- 6- 5，膳食服务对你重要吗？
- What? - Air France, Glasgow direct.
- 什么？ - 法国航空公司，格拉斯哥直航
But then you're looking at the wrong end of 912. That's 9-1-2.
那样的话，你就会看到912，是9- 1- 2
- The first one was fine. Heathrow direct. - It's up to you.
- 第一个很好，伦敦希思罗机场直航 - 随便你
Air Patagonia, that's a new outfit. Via... via lots of different places, really.
巴塔哥尼亚航空公司，全新的装备 途经...途经很多地方，的确
It's no catering. That's 411. 4-1-1. It's good value, but refuelling at Bogot?..
没有膳食服务，是411，4- 1- 1 非常超值，但是要在波哥大加油
The first one was fine.
第一个很好
It's up to you. 7-6-5. How will you be paying?
随便你，7- 6- 5 你打算怎么付款？
Oh, God! Oh, Jesus Christ!
哦，天啊，哦，上帝啊
Oh, my God!
哦，天啊
Christ!
上帝！
No, no. Dear God. No! Christ!
不，不，上帝，不！上帝！
No, and that's it. I refuse to discuss it any further.
不，就这样，我拒绝再继续讨论
- It's the only way. - I refuse.
- 这是唯一的办法 - 我拒绝
- You're frightened. - I'm not frightened. I'm a little terrified.
- 你怕了 - 我不怕，我只是受一点点惊吓
Did you see what happened to the last two people?
你有没有看见最后两个人是怎么样的？
They went up alive and they came back down dead.
他们活着上去，死着下来
Did you notice that? The difference, I mean. Alive, dead - dead, alive.
你看到了吗？我的意思是，不一样了 活的，死的，死的，活的
It wasn't difficult to spot.
不难发现
He killed them both.
他把他们都宰了
- He cut them up. - Yeah, but you'll be all right.
- 他把他们都砍死了 - 是的，但你会好好的
- And how's that? - Because you're smarter than he is.
- 为什么？ - 因为你比他聪明
Yeah, well, that's what I've always thought.
是，我也一直这么认为的
Good evening. I'm Detective Inspector McCall. This is DC Mitchell.
晚上好，我是探长马克，这位是DC 米切尔
I wonder if we could ask some questions.
我们能不能问你几个问题?
- What about? - It's about the burglary.
- 关于什么？ - 关于那起入室行窃
- Burglary? - Downstairs.
- 入室行窃？ - 在楼下
- Of course. - Can we come in?
- 哦，是的 - 我们可以进来吗？
So I just heard her cries for help and all that.
我当时只是听到她的哭声和求救声，仅此而已
When I went downstairs, there were other people there.
当我下楼后，那里还有很多其它的人
So I just stood around, you know, waiting, the way people do.
所以我就站在那里，等着，和其它人一样
And when your colleagues arrived, I came back upstairs.
当你的同事到了之后，我就上楼了
That's about all, I think. I didn't actually see anything useful, I don't think.
就这些，我没有看到任何有价值的东西，没有
And the other three people, did they hear anything?
其它的三个人，他们有没有听到什么？
There are only two other people in the flat.
只有其它两个人在这所公寓里
- Two? - Who said there were four?
- 两个？ - 谁说有四个人？
We understood there were four people living here. Not always, but now four.
我们以为有四个人住在这里， 并不一直是，但现在是四个
No, three. Who said there were four?
不，三个，谁告诉你们有四个人？
How strange. And how unsatisfactory to have misleading information.
真奇怪，这种误导信息实在令人无法满意
Only three people here?
这里只有三个人？
- You're sure? - Yes, absolutely.
- 你肯定？ - 是的，绝对肯定
Who said there were four?
是谁说有四个？
Make a note of that, Mitchell. Only three rather than four. Write it down.
记录下来，米切尔， 只有三个人，而不是四个，记下来
You can use numbers or words. I've no preference.
你可以用数字或文字，我无所谓
- Which are you using? - Both, sir.
- 你用哪一个？ - 全部
Excellent.
好极了
DC Mitchell is a rising star, Mr Stevens.
DC 米切尔是个有前途的明星， 史蒂文斯先生
Under my tutelage, he will undoubtedly make the grade.
在我的监护下，他绝对会升级的
- I see. - I doubt it.
- 了解 - 我比较怀疑
- You'll wait in the hall? - I'll wait.
- 你在大厅里等？ - 是的
If it sounds like I'm getting killed, call the police and tell them everything.
如果听起来象是我被杀死了， 马上打电话给警察，告诉他们一切
Except maybe that it was his idea in the first place.
除非是他首先提出这个主意
That's important. I need to die misunderstood.
那很重要，我不想让他们知道 我死的真正原因
- Alex. - What?
- 亚历克斯 - 什么？
As smart as you are, you might need a little help.
虽然你很聪明，但还是可能需要一点帮助
David, what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna open this lock and I'm gonna come up.
大卫，我要上来，打开这个保险箱
But what's really important is that you remain calm. OK?
重要是的你要保持冷静，好吗？
Alex?
亚历克斯?
It's all right. It's just a pigeon.
没什么，一只鸽子
Well, he isn't up here.
他不在上面
Tell him to look for the money.
叫他找钱
Look for the money.
找一下钱在哪里
Don't worry. That's exactly what I'm doin'.
不要担心，我正在找
It's not up here. He has eaten it.
不在上面，他独吞了
Are you looking for me?
你在找我？
Looking for you, yeah.
对，在找你
What for? What did you want? The money? Was that it?
为什么？你想要什么？ 钱？是吗？
We just wanted to talk to you.
我们只是想和你谈谈
Who else have you just wanted to talk to? Maybe you thought they'd already got me.
你还想和谁谈？ 也许你以为他们已经盯上我了
- Who? - Your friends.
- 谁？ - 你的朋友们
I don't know what you're talkin' about.
我不知道你在说什么
He doesn't know, David.
他不知道，大卫
Maybe you don't.
也许他不知道
I'm talking about the police.
我说的是警察
I thought you'd gone to work.
我以为你去上班了
With a face like this?
带着这张脸？
Alex, the editor wants to see you.
亚历克斯，编辑要见你
- I'm sorry. - So you should be.
- 对不起 - 你应该的
Maybe we can still sort everything out.
也许我们还是可以把事情解决的
Well, we can certainly try.
我们当然可以试试
Three bodies. Decomposed. Mutilated beyond recognition.
三具尸体，已经腐烂 毁容，无法辨认
- I don't know anythin' about it. - Of course you don't.
- 我什么也不知道 - 你当然不知道
If you knew anything about it, I wouldn't have to send you to cover it.
如果你知道什么，我就不用派你去调查了
- Cover it? - That's right. This is your break, son.
- 调查？ - 对，你也可以乘机休息一下
Cover it?
调查？
Jesus.
天啊
Ow!
哦！
All right. The releasable and printworthy facts of the day so far are as follows.
好的，今天到目前为止， 有如下几件事是值得报道的
Late yesterday, forestry workers came across one set of human remains...
昨天晚些时候，森林工人发现一具死尸
..in a grave which appeared to have been recently dug.
埋的地方看起来最近被挖掘过
Further excavation revealed another deeper grave with two sets of remains.
进一步的挖掘后，又发现了另外两具尸体
- Is this a serial killer? - How come they haven't been identified?
- 是连环杀人案吗？ - 为什么他们还没有被辨认出来？
- Any obvious motive here? - Is it true that one has been skinned?
- 有没有明显的动机？ - 有一个人被剥了皮是真的吗？
Not entirely.
并不完全是这样
All right, all right. An area of skin "has" been removed.
好的，好的，有一处皮肤被剥掉了
And you'd better keep this to yourselves. There's no hands, no feet, no teeth.
也许你们对这个感兴趣： 没有手，没有脚，也没有了牙齿
The face is totally unrecognisable and, yes,...
脸部完全无法辨认，是的...
..skin has been removed from one of the bodies.
有一具尸体的皮肤被剥掉了
As and when the corpses are removed,...
当尸体被清理后...
..we will endeavour to ascertain the mode of death and duration of burial,...
我们会尽力找出杀人动机和死亡时间
..as well as identification, which will of course be passed on to you,...
以及被害人身份，
..after informing, where possible, the next of kin.
可能的话，在通知家属以后， 这些都会告诉你们
- Are you OK? - Yes, of course.
- 你还好吗？ - 是的，当然
Why wouldn't I be?
怎么会不好？
- I don't know. I just thought maybe... - We were just sorting things out.
- 我不知道，我以为也许... - 我们刚才在研究问题
- You'd better read all about it. - We already know.
- 你最好看一下这个 - 我们已经知道了
It was on the television.
电视里有
Of course, but print provides a more lucid and...
当然，不过指纹提供了更明确的...
Oh, shut up, Alex.
闭嘴，亚历克斯
It wasn't deep enough. I told you it wasn't deep enough and you wouldn't listen.
不够深，我告诉过你挖的不够深，你就是不听
It doesn't necessarily matter.
这没关系
They don't know who they are and have nothing to connect us with them. Nothing.
他们不知道那些人是谁， 也没有线索关联到我们，没有
I'm glad you're so certain, Alex.
我真高兴你如此肯定，亚历克斯
It makes us feel a whole lot better.
这令我们好受多了
- I beg your pardon? - It makes us feel a whole lot better.
- 请再说一遍？ - 这令我们感觉好多了
That's what I thought he said.
我就知道他会这么说
Shh. Stop.
嘘，停
What are you doin' here?
你在这儿干什么？
It's about me and David.
关于我和大卫
- The perfect couple, I should say. - You mustn't take it so badly.
- 你们真是完美的一对啊 - 你不用这个样子
Don't worry. I'd do exactly the same thing, only I don't think I'm his type.
不要担心，换了我，我也会这么做 只不过，我不是他要的类型
- Don't you ever stop? - No.
- 你就不能住口？ - 不行
Take all the time you like, Doctor.
不用急，医生
No, I've never seen any of them.
没有，我从来没见过他们
Look again, if you like.
再看看，如果你愿意的话
I'm sorry, I haven't seen them.
对不起，我没见过他们
- Do you have a good memory for faces? - The same as everyone else.
- 你对脸的记忆力好吗？ - 和其它人一样
But in your work you must meet lots of people every day. New people, new faces.
但是你工作的时候，你一定每天遇到很多人 新的人，新的面孔
Yes.
是的
What do you recognise most, names or faces?
你能记得他们大多数人的名字，脸吗？
Diseases.
疾病
Like recognising criminals by their crimes.
就象通过犯罪手法认出罪犯一样
- I suppose so. - I meant, that's what it's like.
- 我想是的 - 我是说，就是这个样子的
- Sorry? - You said you supposed so.
- 对不起？ - 你说你想是的？
- I wasn't offering it for debate. - He wasn't offering it for debate.
- 我说这个并不是想争辩 - 他不是想争辩
Like recognising criminals by their crimes.
就象根据犯罪手法认出罪犯一样
No, I've never seen any of these men before.
没有，我从来没见过这些人
Take a look at the first two.
看看开头的两个人
No, I don't know them.
不，我不认识他们
If I told you their car was parked outside just now, would that surprise you?
如果我告诉你们他们的车现在就停在外面， 你会不会觉得奇怪？
Yes, I suppose so.
是，我想是
Well, is it?
是真的吗？
- What? - Parked there?
- 什么？ - 停在哪里？
No. Not any more.
不，现在不在了
I just wondered if it would surprise you.
我只是想，是否会令你奇怪
- That's it. - That's all?
- 就这样 - 就这些？
Yes.
是的
- Sorry to waste your time. - Oh, not at all. Don't worry.
- 很抱歉浪费了你的时间 - 哦，没有，没关系
- One thing. - Your watch.
- 问你件事 - 你的手表
- Is it real?
- 是真货吗
Oh, no. It's a fake. I got it in Thailand. The second hand doesn't sweep.
哦，不，这是个假的，我从泰国买的 秒针已经不会动了
- I see. - Right.
- 了解 - 好
Tell you what. If you do remember these guys,...
跟你说，如果你想起这几个家伙...
..maybe you could give me a phone on this number.
请打这个电话号码和我联系
Any time you like.
任何时间都可以
I didn't tell them anything, nothing at all, absolutely nothing. They're plods.
我什么也没有告诉他们，绝对没有 他们只是问问
If they had any witnesses, any forensic evidence, they would have whipped it out.
如果他们有任何的证人，证据， 早就说出来了
- They know. - They can know all they like.
- 他们知道 - 他们想知道什么就能知道什么
- So? They know.
- 他们知道又怎样？
So what? There's nothing to connect us with that body stuff.
又怎样？没有任何线索可以 把我们和死尸联系起来
- Except the money. - He's right, Alex. They know.
- 除了钱 - 他是正确的，亚历克斯，他们知道
Come on.
拜托接电话
My office is closed.
我们办公室已经关闭了
Life, however, grinds on towards its conclusion.
但是生命仍然在前进
In the meantime, you may wish to leave a message, but the final decision is yours.
你也许想要留个口信 但决定权是你的
David? You forgot to wake me.
大卫？你忘记叫我醒我了
- So let's go. - You and me?
- 那我们走吧 - 你和我？
Together.
一起
Hey! Alex! Who are you calling at this time of night?
嘿！亚历克斯！你这么晚还在打电话给谁？
Come out here and talk to us.
到这儿来，和我们说说话
Well? Sex lines, is that it?
是不是春宵热线啊？对吗？
Triple-X-rated, interactive fantasies? Old habits die hard.
成人服务，交互性幻想 老毛病了，改不掉
- I was phoning your mother. - You old devil.
- 我刚才正在给你妈妈打电话 - 你这个老恶魔
Well, anyway. As you can see, we're leaving.
好了，你已经看到，我们马上要走了
- So I gathered. - I'm sorry, but that's the way it is.
- 我整理好东西了 - 对不起，就是这个样子
- Don't worry. I'll forward your mail. - No, really.
- 不要担心，我会把你的邮件转发给你的 - 不用了
I am sorry. Sorry to be ducking out on you. I hope you won't take it personally.
对不起，我没有通知你，希望你不要介意
No, no. Don't let it worry you. It's probably for the best.
不，不，不要担心，这样大概最好了
All for the best. Exactly. I wouldn't want things to end on a downer.
这样最好，我也不想看到大家沮丧
- Not at all. - I mean, we've ups and downs, right.
- 完全没有 - 我是说，人生有起有伏
Good times, bad times.
有顺境，有逆境
We could talk all night, but we have to go. Don't we?
我们可以彻夜长谈，不过我们要走了，对吧？
Yes.
是的
- And you need your sleep. - Yes.
- 而你也应该去睡觉了 - 是的
No, I can't think of anything else that matters.
一点也不要紧
- About your mail. - Very good of you to offer, but...
- 关于你的信件 - 你这样很好，但是...
Where do you think you'll go?
你打算去哪里？
Where will we go?
我们去哪儿?
Juliet?
朱丽叶?
- I don't know. - Don't be so coy, dear.
- 我不知道 - 别害羞啊，亲爱的
You're going to Rio.
你要去里约热内卢啊
- What? - That's right.
- 什么？ - 对
Rio de Janeiro, on your own.
里约热内卢，你一个人
You should know. You bought the fucking ticket!
你应该知道，你自己买的那该死的机票！
Did you see that?
你看见了吗？
I bet she didn't show you that before she sent you up there. What did she say?
我敢打赌，在她叫你上阁楼之前 没让你见过这个吧？她之前说了什么？
We'll split it together, you and me, fifty-fifty.
我们把钱分掉，一人一半
But I bet you didn't say you'd split on him.
但我敢打赌，你没有说过要分给他一份
- It wasn't like that. - Don't lie to me. Don't treat me like that.
- 不是这样的 - 不要骗我，不要对我这样
I bought it.
我买的
What?
什么？
I bought the tickets. For her and for me. It was my idea.
我买的机票，她的和我的，是我的主意
Your idea. I see.
你的主意，我知道了
Well, that fits.
那就对了
I mean, you and him fit together. I should have seen that a long time ago.
我是说，你和她很相衬 我早就应该看出来的
- Alex, stop him! - No, let him go. Let him have it all.
- 亚历克斯，阻止他！ - 不，让他走，让他带着所有的钱走
Juliet, let him go.
朱丽叶，让他走
I'm leaving.
我要走了
You shouldn't have hit her! Do what you like, but you shouldn't have hit her!
你不应该打她！ 你想怎么样都行，但不可以打她！
You want it?
你想要？
You bastard!
你这个混蛋！
You did the right thing.
你做的对
But I can't take you with me.
但我不能带你走
Be OK, Mummy.
保重，妈啊
Oh, I'll be all right.
哦，我会很好的
Hello, Inspector.
你好，探长
Oh, yes. I believe in friends.
哦，是的，我相信朋友
I believe we need them.
我相信我们需要朋友
But, if one day you find that you just can't trust them any more,...
但是如果有一天， 你发现你再也无法相信他们...
..well what then?
那怎么办?
What then?
怎么办?